ncld.org 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy - NCLD

This Privacy Policy describes how NCLD collects and uses information from all end users of our organization’s Websites, including LD.org; GetReadytoRead.org; RTINetwork.org; and RecognitionandResponse.org. NCLD requests that you read this Privacy Policy carefully.

* * *

###  **How NCLD Collects and Uses Visitor Information**

NCLD uses third-party vendors in the collection of visitor information. Our data is held privately and we do not share personally identifiable information with any other third party, except for our partners and sponsors including, Understood.org USA LLC (“Understood”) and the Poses Family Foundation (“Poses”). NCLD is the sole owner of the information collected on our sites. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways other than as disclosed in this statement.

* * *

###  **Charitable Contributions**

We may use a vendor, such as payment processor, to help assist us in delivering NCLD.org to you for purposes of making donations. In some cases you may be required to submit personal information (such as your name and address) and financial information (such as a credit card number) to these vendors. We will use a vendor that meets the necessary security requirements for these purposes.  We will keep your personal information (e.g., name, email address, phone number, address) and financial information (e.g., payment card details) provided in connection with your donation private and will not rent, share or sell your information without your consent, other than for purposes of processing your donation and as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy.

* * *

###  **Log Files**

We may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer our sites, track users’ movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

* * *

###  **Sharing Information**

We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and sponsors. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

The information that a user submits on our sites will be provided to (i) our vendors on a confidential basis for the sole purpose of delivering NCLD’s communications to users who have ‘opted in’ to receive them and (ii) our partners and sponsors including, Understood and Poses, for the purpose of providing certain information and services to you. Visitor email addresses will not be shared with any other third parties.

We may, however, release information provided by a user to the extent it is required to be disclosed pursuant to a valid order or requirement of a governmental agency or court.

* * *

###  **Registration**

Visitors are required to provide certain personal information when they join our online community or subscribe to our newsletter(s), such as name and email address. We may ask for additional information, but the submission of that information is strictly voluntary. The information collected from visitors during the registration process is used to help NCLD develop content for the Web sites, collect audience information, and to develop our and our partners’ Web community, particularly for advocacy and fundraising purposes. This information is not shared with third parties other than our partners and sponsors including, Understood and Poses. When visitors register on our site, they may receive an email from Understood. Should a visitor not wish to receive additional emails from Understood, the visitor may opt-out of those emails.

* * *

###  **About External Links and Partner Organizations**

NCLD has partnered with other organizations or companies to provide certain services, such as ecommerce or facilitate communications with our constituents. In some cases, visitors may see NCLD’s logo on another organization or company’s site.

Once visitors leave our servers (evident by checking the URL in the location bar on a web browser), the use of any information provided is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site being visited. That policy may differ from ours. If visitors can’t find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from that site’s home page, they should contact the site directly for more information.

* * *

###  **Online Shopping**

NCLD offers products through an online store; we choose products that we believe are of high quality and could be of value to parents, professionals, or individuals with learning disabilities. NCLD does not recommend or endorse any of these program and services (see “disclosure” statement). Visitors should use their own discretion in choosing products that best meet your needs.

At some Web sites linked to by our sites, visitors can purchase products and services or register to receive materials, such as a catalog or new product and service updates. In many cases, visitors may be asked to provide contact and credit/debit card information. If completing an order for someone else, such as an online gift order sent directly to a recipient, visitors may be asked to provide information about the recipient, such as the recipient’s name or contact information. NCLD has no control over the third parties’ use of any personal information provided when placing such an order. Visitors are encouraged to exercise care when doing so.

* * *

###  **Responses to Email Inquiries**

NCLD does not share the email addresses from inquiries made to our sites with any third party and will only use the email address provided to answer inquiries.

* * *

###  **Disclaimer**

The contents of NCLD’s Web sites are intended for informational use only and do not necessarily reflect the views of NCLD, its officers, or directors. Information contained on these pages is intended to increase understanding of learning disabilities and provide high quality resources to parents, professionals and individuals with LD. While it does not recommend or endorse specific products or programs, it does advocate for responsible decision-making and in certain instances will promote activities that have proved effective in addressing the needs of individuals with LD.

* * *

###  **Voluntary Customer Surveys**

We may periodically conduct visitor surveys and we encourage our users to participate in them. We take the information we receive from individuals responding to these surveys and aggregate it with the responses of other visitors. This aggregated information is then used to improve the quality of our services and information to visitors, and to develop new services and products. Any personal information and responses may be shared with our partners and sponsors including, Understood and Poses but will, at all times, remain strictly confidential, even if the survey is conducted by a third party. Participation in our customer surveys is voluntary.

* * *

###  **“Cookies” and How NCLD Uses Them**

A “cookie” is a small data file that can be placed on a visitor’s hard drive when visiting certain Web sites. NCLD may use cookies only to collect, store, and sometimes track information for statistical purposes to improve the information and services we provide and to manage our telecommunications networks. These cookies do not enable third parties to access any of our visitors’ information.

Advertisers, linked sites, and partners may also use their own cookies. We do not control use of these cookies and expressly disclaim responsibility for information collected through them.

* * *

###  **NCLD’s Commitment to Children’s Privacy**

Protecting children’s privacy is especially important to us. We have Web pages designed especially for our younger users. While we make every effort to ensure that these Web sites are fun and age-appropriate for our younger audience, we believe that there is no substitute for proper parental supervision. For further information about tips, tools, age-appropriate or kid-friendly Web sites and how to report online trouble, please visit Getnetwise.org. Finally, NCLD recommends that children ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to NCLD or to anyone else online.

* * *

###  **Public Forums**

Please remember that any information visitors may disclose in our public areas of our Web sites, such as comment sections, discussion boards or blogs, becomes public information. We advise visitors to exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these public areas.

* * *

###  **NCLD’s Commitment to Data Security**

The services and Web sites we sponsor have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. NCLD has implemented reasonable technical and organizational measures designed to secure visitors personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, or disclosure. When users submit personal information via our Web sites, NCLD uses reasonable efforts to protect their information both online and offline. The servers that are used to store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use visitors’ personal information for improper purposes. Thus, visitors to our web sites acknowledge that that any personal information provided is done so at their own risk.

NCLD has contractual agreements with the Blackbaud and Convio companies, both of which offer assurances that they protect personal information of it’s clients. Blackbaud provides donation fulfillment services, and Convio is used for outreach to individuals who have voluntarily subscribed to receive online communications from NCLD. These vendors offer the following specific terms of engagement:

 _“All information provided to Covio is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our Site that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of Convio.”_

 _“Blackbaud Payment Services has passed its PCI DSS audit and has been certified as a Level 1 Payment Gateway Service Provider.”_

* * *

###  **Compromise of Security**

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, NCLD will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

* * *

###  **Where to Direct Questions about NCLD’s Privacy Policy**

If visitors have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices described herein, or have any questions about the use of contact information, they may email [support@ncld.org](mailto:support@ncld.org) or call 646-757-3135.

* * *

###  **Revisions to This Policy**

NCLD reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this policy and our other policies and agreements at any time and in any manner. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use personal information in a way that materially differs from this Privacy Policy, including sharing such information with more third parties, we will post such changes here and you may choose not to accept those changes by emailing us at the above address and requesting that we delete your personal information provided in connection with your registration. Your continued use of our organization’s Web sites and associated services following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy means you accept such changes. Further, we are not responsible for removing your personal information from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided with your information in accordance with this policy.
